dondengaeshi detatokoshoubu nerau wa ittou shou
An unexpected ending, deal with it as it comes,
we're aiming for first place
i can feel it donna toki datte hikari o shinjiteru
I Can Feel it, no matter what, I believe in the light
nigirishime ta yume ga koboreochi sou na
When the dream I've attained is
toki ni kagitte omoidasu no
about to fall apart, I remember
aitsu no ano yasashii kao
His kind expression,
mune no oku ga mata tsuyoku nareru no
the core of my heart is strengthened once again
bukkirabou no kokoro ni fire
My blunt mind is set ablaze,
gutto kuru ashita o tsukami tain da
I want to grasp tomorrow as it comes at me
mada mi nu sekai wa kowaku nai
I'm not afraid of the world I haven't seen,
shinji ta mirai desho hora let’s try!
isn't this the future we believed in? Come on Let's try!
kazoekire nai ano namida wa sou sa niji ni kawaru darou
Those countless tears, will they change into a rainbow?
osaekire nai kanashimi mo
That sorrow I can't contain
itsuka wa dakishime rareru ka na
Will I be able to embrace you someday?
yawa na haato ga uzukidashi tara
When my feeble heart begins to throb
arittake asu ni kisu shite ageyou
I give all of my kisses to tomorrow
furue ta mama no chiisana kobushi o tsuyoku mata nigitte
Still trembling, I clench my tiny fist tightly
dondengaeshi detatokoshoubu nerau wa ittou shou
An unexpected ending, deal with it as it comes,
we're aiming for first place
i can feel it donna toki datte hikari o shinjiteru
I Can Feel it, no matter what, I believe in the light
The Two Mangekyo
(マダラ)ゼツ… いつまで オビトに
へばりついている？
Zetsu... How long are you going
to cling to Obito?
(ゼツ)すみません ですが コイツらから
九尾の半身も奪っておきました。
Sorry...
But that allowed me to steal Nine Tails'
other half from these guys.
(マダラ)よし！
左目とあわせて持ってこい。
Good. Now bring it,
and my left eye, to me.
《ミナト : 仙人の力を感じる
これは オビトのときよりも更に…》
I sense Sage Power...
And it's much stronger than
what Obito possessed.
(我愛羅)やはり 四代目の九尾は
あの黒いヤツの中か…。
So the Fourth Hokage's Nine Tails
is inside that black thing!
(カカシ)マダラ どうやって六道の力を？
Madara?!
How did he get Six Paths' power?
マダラ様がいるかぎり
コイツから離れても→
Since Lord Madara is here,
you can't do anything to me...
お前らは
俺になんにもできはしない。
even if I separate myself
from Obito.
うっ!?
Now, Kakashi!
いくぞ カカシ！
うっ！ うぅ…。
(オビト)ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
キサマ まだ…。
Why you—!
You're still—!
まだだ… アンタに話がある。 マダラ。
Not yet...
I need to
ask you something, Madara.
ナルトには ヤツの中の九尾が必要だ。
We need the Nine Tails inside
that thing for Naruto.
失敗はできない。
We cannot afford to miss.
ここぞというときでなければダメだ。
We have to wait for
the right moment.
アンタにとって 俺はなんだ？
Just what am I... to you?
(マダラ)フフフ…。
冗談はよせ。
You're kidding, right?
What kind of a stupid question is that,
at this point in time?
今更 くだらないことを聞くな。
お前は 俺にとって
他でもない→
You are only one thing to me...
マダラだ。
You are Madara.
《マダラ : さあ 動け
俺が復活するまでの間→
Now go...
Until the time when
I am revived...
お前が うちはマダラだ》
You shall be Madara Uchiha.
この世界を否定する存在が マダラだ。
Madara is he who rejects the world.
その思想を胸に行動し→
All who hold that in their heart...
無限月読の計画を狙う者は→
and strive toward achieving
the Infinite Tsukuyomi are Madara.
すべて マダラでしかない。
それは…。
That...
それは俺の道でもあった。
That was once my path too.
俺が眠りにつき帰るまでの間→
I left you in charge of everything...
お前に すべてを任せ→
And let you walk in my shoes,
while I slept, waiting to return.
俺の先を歩かせてやったのだ。
それは俺が示してやった道だ。
It's the path I guided you towards.
お前は目的達成のために→
You were supposed to live out
your life as Madara
マダラとして
天寿を全うするはずだった。
in order to achieve our goal.
この世界を救った救世主としてな。
As the savior who rescued this world.
六道仙人が示した この世界は→
This world laid out by
the Sage of the Six Paths...
失敗した。
has failed.
いいか。
Now listen...
六道の広めたチャクラとは→
The chakra dispersed by
the Six Paths was originally...
本来 繋ぐ力のことだ。
meant to be a linking power.
人と人の精神エネルギーを繋ぎ→
The mental energies of people
would connect and feelings
言葉なくとも
互いの心を理解し合い→
would be understood without
the need for words...
人々の安定を願うもの。
That would lead to peace and stability.
その力を忍宗として説き→
The one who preached this
as Ninshu, the Ninja Creed
NINSHU
人々に伝え導こうとしたのが
六道仙人だ。
and sought to guide the people,
was the Sage of the Six Paths.
だが人々は いつしか
互いの心を繋げるためではなく→
However...
But before long, people used chakra
not to connect with others
己の中の精神エネルギーと→
but only to link the mental and
physical energies within themselves.
身体エネルギーを繋ぐために
チャクラを使った。
己のチャクラを大きく練り上げ
増幅する方法で。
Through a method of infusing one's
own chakra and increasing it multifold...
武力となる忍術へと
チャクラを変換するためにな。
they changed chakra into ninjutsu
that could be used as weapons in battle.
皮肉にも六道の母 カグヤが→
Ironically reverting to the way
Six Paths' mother, Kaguya,
武力として チャクラを使用した道に
戻ったわけだ。
had originally used chakra.
(サクラ)いったい
何の話をしてるの？ コイツ。
Just what the hell is
he talking about?!
我愛羅。
わかっている。
Gaara...
I know.
六道仙人の行いは
人の矛盾を助長したにすぎん。
All the Sage of the Six Paths did was
to further the human paradox.
そして たとえ
心と 心を繋げたところで→
And even if bonds were established...
わかり合えないのが
わかるだけだったのだ。
All they learned was that
true understanding was not possible.
どちらにしろ
チャクラは 争いを生み→
In any case, chakra only gives rise
to conflict and false hope.
まやかしの希望を生むだけだった。
俺も お前たちも
平和を追い求めるのと同時に→
We all know the reality all too well...
争いを求めてきた現実がある。
Even as we seek peace,
we seek war.
この現実は
チャクラという力によって→
And this reality compels
infinite suffering
無限の苦しみを強いられている。
through the power known as chakra.
力があるから 争いを望み→
Power leads to the desire for war.
力がないから すべてを失う。
And the lack of power leads
to losing everything.
俺は それを乗り越えた
新たな世界をつくる。
I will build a new world
that overcomes that!
無限月読により→
Through the Infinite Tsukuyomi,
いまわしき チャクラなき
夢の世界をつくるのだ。
I will create a dream world
without any abominable chakra!
最後にして 最強のチャクラを持つ
この俺が導く。
I, who possess the most
powerful chakra, shall lead it!
そして お前は 俺そのものだ。
オビトではない。
And you are not Obito,
but me... Madara himself.
(マダラ)うちはオビトは
うちはのチャクラがあるがゆえに→
Obito Uchiha with his Uchiha Chakra,
challenged Kakashi Hatake,
はたけカカシに挑戦し 火影を望み→
desired the title of Hokage,
and yearned for Rin Nohara!
のはらリンを望んだ。
だが その力が
まやかしだったがために→
But because his power was false,
he ended up losing everything!
そのすべてを失ったのだ。
ここは 地獄だ。 忘れたのか!?
This is hell!
Have you forgotten?!
こっちへ来い。
Come over here.
来い。 そう マダラよ。
Yes, come, Madara!
今日から お前が救世主だ。
From this day forth,
you are a savior.
今でも お前は 救世主のはずだ。
You are still the savior, even now.
砂漠波！
Sand Wave!
神威！
Kamui!
仙術！
Sage Jutsu!
螺旋丸！
Rasengan!
うおっ…。
そ… そんな ３人の攻撃が。
No way...
Their combined attack...
さあ…。
Now...
キサマ…。
You damned...
何のマネだ!?
What are you doing?!
((オビト : いや…
俺のやっていることは→
No...
What I'm doing is no different
than a Hokage's actions.
火影と何ら変わらない。
それ以上だ。
In fact, it's greater.
平和を実現できるのだからな。
Because I can truly
bring about peace.
険しい道だと わかっていて
歩くことはない。
There's no need to voluntarily
walk down a path
you know to be dangerous.
仲間の死体をまたぐだけだ。
You'll have to step over
the corpses of your friends.
それは俺が示してやった道だ。
It's the path I guided you to.
(ナルト)俺が知りてえのは
楽な道のりじゃねえ。
I don't want to know the easy path.
お前に すべてを任せ
俺の先を歩かせてやったのだ。
I left you in charge of everything...
And let you walk in my shoes...
火影ってのは 痛ぇのガマンして→
The Hokage is the one who
walks ahead of everyone else,
(みんなの前を
歩いているヤツのことだ))
who endures the pain.
人を導く者は 己の死体を
またがれることがあっても→
One who leads others...
is one who never steps
over his friends' corpses...
仲間の死体を
またいだりはしないらしい。
even if his own ends up
being stepped on.
なら それを確かめるために
まず お前が死体にならねばな。
Then in order to confirm that,
you'll have to become a corpse.
(オビト)俺はもう
アンタにまたがれることもない。
You won't be
stepping on me anymore.
己の名を騙らせ
他人にすべてを任せることは→
I realize now that letting someone
handle everything in your name
仲間に託すこととは違うと
今なら わかる。
isn't the same as truly
entrusting them with the task.
(オビト)俺は アンタじゃない。
I am not you.
((リン : 頑張れオビト。
Go for it, Obito!
火影になって かっこよく
世界を救うとこ 見せてね！
Become the Hokage
and save the world!
(それも 約束だよ！))
That's a promise too!
今の俺は 火影を語りたかった
うちはオビトだ！
The current me...
is the one who wanted
to be Hokage... Obito Uchiha!
Obito...
オビト…。
Obito... You've finally found yourself!
《オビト… お前やっと自分を…》
I passed through you.
すり抜ける。
お前 本来の右目の力か。
That's your original right eye's power.
Are you trying to weaken me
by taking away the Tailed Beasts?
俺から尾獣を奪い
弱体化を狙っているのか？
Do you think you can
challenge me and win?!
俺と取り合って
勝てると思っているとはな。
So weak...
弱いな。 一尾と八尾を
ほんの少し引きちぎった程度とは。
Is that all? You only tore off
a mere sliver of the One and Eight Tails?
Kakashi!
カカシ！ ナルトを時空間へ運べ！
Take Naruto into the Time-Space!
Obito plans to hand him
the Nine Tails there!
《オビトは あっちで
九尾を渡すつもりなのか？
Kamui!
神威！》
(サクラ)うわっ！
《神威！》
Kamui!
I know that when you teleport
your body materializes...
《自ら飛ぶときに
体が実体化するのは知っている》
If I try to teleport carelessly,
he'll come after me.
《うかつに時空間に
飛ぼうとすれば→
その隙を狙われる。
空間移動スピードが遅すぎる》
My teleportation speed is too slow.
Since he'd been in Sage mode once,
一度 仙人化しただけはある。
he was able to steal some
Sage Power from me too...
ほんの少しだが 俺から
その力まで吸い取ったか。
Madara...
《マダラ… アイツは
いつでも私を殺せた。
could have killed me at any time...
I was so scared I forgot to breathe!
あまりの恐怖で
息をするのも忘れてた。
アイツは… アイツだけは次元が違う》
Of all the people,
he's in a different class!
All right, I transported Naruto.
(カカシ)ナルトは運んだ。
All that's left is for you
to teleport yourself there
あとは お前が向こうへ飛べば
ナルトは助かるってことだな？
and Naruto will be saved, right, Obito?
(カカシ)オビト。
フン… まったく。
Damn it.
You always talk down to me...
お前は いつも上から目線で→
And act so superior...
Just like old times.
偉そうなことばかり言ってやがる。
昔から そうだ。
Obito!
((オビト。
Rin is here to pick you up.
リンちゃんが迎えにきたぞよ。
(オビト)ごめん ごめん リン！
Sorry, sorry, Rin!
早く ひ孫の顔が
見たいのう オビトよ。
I can't wait to see
my great-grandchild's face, Obito.
Grandma, I'm only five years old.
(オビト)ばあちゃん
俺 まだ５つだぞ？
Come on, hurry,
it's going to start!
早く 早く！ 始まっちゃうよ！
YOUTH NINJUTSU COMPETITION
お～っ！ これが賞品のクナイか！
Wow! This is the kunai prize!
It's so cool!
かっこいいね！
Okay, thank you very much!
はい どうも
ありがとうございました。
I wonder what kind of
ninjutsu is next?
さて 次は どんな忍術かな？
ヘヘッ このメンツなら
優勝いただきだぜ。
If these are the opponents,
this is going to be a piece of cake.
Number seven, Obito Uchiha!
７番 うちはオビト君！
That's me!
俺だ！
Go for it, Obito!
頑張れ オビト！
What are you going
to show us, Obito?
オビト君は
何をやってくれるのかな？
I'm going to be doing
the Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
俺は火遁 豪火球の術をやるぜ。
おお すごいね！
Wow, impressive!
All right, let's get right to it!
それじゃ よろしく。
いくぜ!!
Here I go!
火遁 豪火球の術！
Fire Style!
Fireball Jutsu!
Six points! Seven points!
Seven points!
６点 ７点 ７点。
お～っ いい数字が出ました。
These are great numbers!
Obito Uchiha is in
the lead right now!
うちはオビト君が
ここまでのトップです！
That was great, Obito!
すごいね オビト！
ヘヘッ 今日は
ちょっと調子悪かったけど→
I wasn't in top form today,
but I think it's a sure win for me.
これなら
俺の優勝は間違いねえぜ！
All right, here's our final challenger!
それじゃ
最後の挑戦者 はたけカカシ君！
Kakashi Hatake!
What are you doing to do
for us, Kakashi?
カカシ君は
何をやってくれるのかな？
Well, how about
the Earth Style: Mud Wave?
(カカシ)じゃあ 土遁の土波を。
おぉ～ その術は
かなりチャクラがいるけど大丈夫？
Really? That jutsu requires
a considerable amount of chakra.
Are you sure about this?
フン！ 俺たちの歳で土波なんて…。
Mud Wave? At our age?
土遁 土波の術！
Earth Style! Mud Wave Jutsu!
う～ あぁ～！
The judges all agree!
Perfect 10s!
文句なしの満点だ！
The winner is Kakashi Hatake!
優勝は はたけカカシ君！
おめでとう！
Too bad, Obito.
ん～！
残念だったね オビト。
Kakashi... Hatake!
はたけ… カカシ。
遅いよ オビト！ みんな待ってるよ！
You're late, Obito!
Everyone's been waiting!
Sorry, sorry! On the way,
an old man was...
(オビト)ごめん ごめん！
途中でおじいちゃんが…。
《あっ… カカシ！》
Kakashi!
Kakashi's joining us from today!
カカシも今日から仲間に入るって！
今日は 缶蹴りやろうぜ！
Let's play kick-the-can today!
おお！ やろうぜ！
Sure! Let's play!
ハァ… ハァ…。
Kakashi's the only one left.
あとは カカシだけか。
Obito's such a fast runner.
オビトは足が速いからな。
Save us, Kakashi!
助けてくれよ カカシ！
I'll catch him instantly!
すぐ捕まえてやる！
(みんな)おぉ！
What—?!
なっ!?
仲間は絶対に助ける。
Saving my friends, no matter what...
That's my Ninja Way.
それが俺の流儀だ！
(みんな)わぁ～！
ハァハァ…。
ひえ～！
ハァ…。
ダハー！
(カカシ)なんなら鬼をかわろうか？
Want me to be "it"?
As if!
(オビト)誰が！
Obito was "it" the whole time.
ずっとオビトが鬼だったね。
But he couldn't catch Kakashi,
not even once...
でも １回も捕まらないなんて。
Kakashi is amazing.
カカシ すっげえな！
あ 母さん！
Oh, Mom!
オビト 私 帰るね。
Obito, I have to leave.
Me too! Mom!
俺も。
母ちゃん！
I won again.
また俺の勝ちだな。
でも ひとつだけ褒めてやるよ。
But I'll praise you for one thing...
今まで俺に 音を
あげなかったのは お前だけだ。
You're the only one until now
who never chickened out.
フン 偉そうに。
You show off!
Hey, I was praising you.
せっかく褒めてやってるのに。
あ 父さんだ。 じゃあな。
There's my dad! So long!
Yeah... See you!
ああ またな。
Say, Grandma...
なぁ ばあちゃん 俺は
父ちゃん似かな 母ちゃん似かな。
Am I like my dad? Or my mom?
そうだのう 両方かの。
Well, let's see...
I think both of them.
お前は 両親の
命をもらって生きとるんじゃ。
You are alive because
of your parents.
そのぶんも
他の人のために役立たねばのう。
So you must honor them both
and work for the sake of others.
うん。
やべえ やべえ やべえ！
今日だけは→
Oh man, oh man, oh man!
This is the one day I can't be late!
遅刻するわけにはいかねえんだ。
ENTRANCE CEREMONY
ハァー。
It's the entrance ceremony
and you're already late.
入学式から遅刻か。
そんなヤツに
アカデミーに入る資格はない。
Someone like you has no business
being in the Academy.
You'll never make it.
無理だな。
大丈夫よ。
It's okay.
これ ちゃんと
もらっておいたから。
I got this for you.
お 俺の？
ええ。
For me?
Yes! Just submit this and
you'll be able to enroll.
この書類を出せば
問題なく入学できるって。
Thank you! You're a lifesaver!
助かった 恩にきるぜ！
チッ！ 甘やかしてっと
コイツの遅刻癖 直んねえぞ。
Keep pampering him and
he'll never be cured of his tardiness.
Shut up! Do you wanna fight?
うるせぇ！ やるか この！
Say that again!
なにを！
なんだよ！
– What?
– It's your fault!
お前が悪いんだからな。
なんだと… カカシ！
What did you say,
stupid Kakashi?
Kakashi Hatake!
はたけカカシ。
アイツを必ず ブッ倒して→
I'll take him down and become
the Hokage, no matter what!
俺は火影になる！
フフフッ その意気よ。
That's the spirit!
(みんな)ハハハハハッ！
(みんな)おお～！
すごい！
ヘヘヘッ！
Kakashi is different from us, isn't he?
やっぱりカカシは 私たちとは違うね。
What a dummy!
バカなヤツ！ またカカシに挑んで
痛めつけられたんだって。
He challenged Kakashi again
and got his butt kicked.
落ちこぼれが
トップに勝てるわけねえのに。
As if the class loser can beat
the head of the class!
Rin?!
(オビト)リン！
Someday, I'll awaken my Sharingan,
《俺だって
いつか写輪眼が開眼したら→
and I won't lose to him...
アイツになんて 負けねえのに…》
Kakashi hasn't been coming
to class at all lately.
(オビト)カカシのヤツ
最近ずっと休みだな。
I heard something unfortunate
happened to his father.
(リン)なんか お父さんに
不幸があったんですって。
(えっ…。
きっと大変なんだと思う))
I think it's a difficult time
for him right now...
After that, you skipped a grade
and quickly left the Academy.
(オビト)その後 お前は飛び級で
さっさとアカデミーを去っちまった。
Back then, if I had noticed
the huge emptiness in your heart...
あのとき 俺が お前の心にあいた
むなしさに気づいていたら→
maybe our present destiny
might have been a little different.
今の運命も
少しは違っていたのかもしれない。
俺は知らなかった。
I didn't realize how much
the death of your father Sakumo
had changed you...
お前の父 サクモさんの死が→
どれだけ
お前を変えてしまったのかを…。
hitori ja nai yo
You're not alone
osoreru mono nante nai kara
There's nothing to be afraid of
ikou saa me o ake te
Let's go, now open your eyes
butsukatte ita
I was crashing into you
hontou wa oitsuki taku te
I just wanted to catch up so badly
kizutsuke atte
We hurt one another
tsunagi tomeru kizuna hoshiku te
I just wanted a bond to connect me to you
"gomen" wasure nai de
"I'm sorry" Don't forget
shinji te matte te
Trust in me and wait
mukae ni ikun da
I'll come for you
yuuki no tomoshibi terashidase yowa sa o
The light of courage, reveal our weaknesses
kizu datte itami datte wakeae ba heiki da
If we share our wounds and pain, we'll be fine
kimi no senaka osu musun da yakusoku
This is the promise I made you push you forward
itsu datte hanare tatte
No matter when, even if we're apart
shinjirareru kizuna wa mune ni nemutteru
The bond I believe in rests in my heart
Hey Rin, have you seen Kakashi lately?
Why do you ask?
さあ 皆さん
お待ちかねでございます。
I heard a rumor about him yesterday.
ざっと並んだ このメンバーでですな→
It wasn't good,
but he seemed different.
なんと 俺の歌
歌ってくれるんだってさ。
一緒に歌いたい。 皆さんも
知ってたら歌ってちょうだい。
Could it be...?
Do you know something?
いってみよう！
Well, no...
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"The Formation of Team Minato"
Well, see you tomorrow, Obito!
(宮本)６月５日は 北島三郎さんが
デビューした記念の日です。